For the moment, you can see it's a tube, so that means it's
hollow inside.
But at some point, the tissue settles on
my epiblast,
it does this, and then it
closes back into a tube, it's not a tube, what do we call it?
A cord, we can see it looks like that.
Below, I have my hypoblast.
Already, we can almost say the openings of the endoderm.
But the closer we get to a shape, the more it looks...
a bit like this
we enter and really go into a tube
through growth it comes
down, it flattens out
the hypoblast
then it resumes like this
and it restructures
so that it becomes a cord
you need to see that it's a tube
okay
now I’ll just take a section here
and we’ll look inside like this
What do I see? I see this.
I've removed my hector...
I could place above...
I could place the ectoderm above.
The notochord, which at this stage is a tube,
it flattens against my
hypoblast,
to the point that at some moment,
it completely comes in.
and it will become solely
a structure without inner light,
so a cord.
And that's when it will become
ecto-meso-endo, in fact.
At the level of my notochord,
not of my mesoblast.
This is my notochord,
but which is at the stage
of a chordal tube,
and then it will become a chordal cord.
No, the notochord is epiblastic and at the stage where it
closes, it takes hypoblastic information with it.
It is essentially epiblastic.
Do you understand?
It is epiblastic due to all this movement and when it becomes chordal, thus
only a cord, it has information.
hypoblastic with it. This is the neural tube,
this is the vertebra forming here. We can see
already here now the vertebra with the neural tube and we see the
notochord coming here.
And then there will remain this vestige of my notochord.